ISMAEL RAMOS

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

INFO

+34 667 220 558

ramos.silvan.ismael@gmail.com

www.ismaelramos.me

in linkedin.com/in/ramossilvanismael



github.com/ismaestro

ABOUT ME

I have experience in both consulting and startups (I love them). At work I like the environment a little bit freaky, being able to telework from time to time (2 days a week) and have some flexibility with the schedules.

I consider myself proactive, adapted to the changes, constantly learning and hardworking. I've been creating and evolving websites for about 6 years. Step by step. Pixel by pixel.

EXTRA

In addition to bicycling, doing some mountain routes, swimming, playing video games, going to the cinema, and more boring things, I develop other projects in my free time: WP, SPA's with Angular, apps with Ionic and Flutter and some webs with AMP. Also, I usually take care of the SEO and Analytics (GTM) part in a basic way.

SKILLS

Languages Spanish (native) and English (B1)

My day to day Angular, Flutter, Ionic, Typescript,

Javascript, Protractor, Karma, Jasmine,

SASS, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, AMP, SEO,

Gulp, NPM, Git

Learning

Dart and Python

EXPERIENCE

METASTARTUP - FRONT END DEVELOPER

Creation of digital products and services in a startup mode – 05/2018 - present

Currently working as Lead front end developer for the new Santander Bank Scholarships platform and also helping to define the architecture of the project.

I work with Angular 7+, Karma, Jasmine, Cucumber and Protractor as well as Bootstrap 4 with SASS (responsive design).

The backend is build under **micro-services** with **NodeJS**, MongoDB, Redis and Kafka. To deploy we have **Jenkins (CI)** and for containers management, **Kubernetes**

ACCENTURE - FRONT END DEVELOPER

Strategy, Digital Consulting, Technology, and Operations - 01/2017 - 05/2018

Lead front end developer at Trust·u, a fintech initiative of BBVA Bank in startup mode that was dedicated to give loans to young SMEs.

- Programming with **Angular** 5+ and make tests with Protractor, Karma and Jasmine. We use Bootstrap 4, SASS, Gulp and GIT. Error handling with Sentry.
- The architecture was based on micro-services with Docker and Mesos (Decos)
- Special care of application **performance** and **security**
- Support at specific moments to the back end. NodeJS and MongoDB.
- Agile Methodology (SCRUM)

BEST OPTION MEDIA - FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Media agency specialised in performance - 09/2016 - 01/2017

Here I worked in the front of an application to compare sports betting. My objective was to renew and optimise the web transversally.

- Programming with jQuery, CSS3 (SASS and Bootstrap) and AngularJS
- Programming tasks with Gulp and NPM
- Also fix the back office built with PHP and MySQL

During this period, I added tests to the application, improved the SEO of the web, and in the back helped in the design of the database to migrate the data to MongoDB.

TELECOMING - FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Telecommunications operator specialised in payment technologies – 07/2015 - 09/2016

In this company, I worked until the completion of a real-time application to manage call centers (VirtualCenter360).

- Front with **AngularJS** and **jQuery**, in addition to SASS and **Angular Material**
- Back with NodeJS (Express) to create two services, one for Chat (SocketIO) and another for notifications (Sendgrid). PHP (Zend Framework) to program the back office.
- Tests with PHPUnit in the back and Karma, Jasmine and Protractor in the front
- Use of **Redis**, Memcached, Beanstalkd and **Jenkins**
- Others: GIT, Gulp and NPM

ISMAEL RAMOS

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

INFO

+34 667 220 558

ramos.silvan.ismael@gmail.com

www.ismaelramos.me

Inkedin.com/in/ramossilvanismael

github.com/ismaestro

COURSES

MongoDB for NodeJS developers

Mongo University - 2017

MongoDB security

Mongo University - 2016

Augmented reality on Android devices

University of Oviedo - 2012

Editing and programming documents and presentations in LaTeX

University of Oviedo - 2011

AWARDS

Educational Digital Circuit Simulator (SECD) - With honours

University of Oviedo - 2013

It was my final project. SECD is a tool to create digital circuits and simulate their behaviour. It is made in Java (Swing framework). Currently it is still used in the signatures of the degree.

ENVISTA CULTURA VISUAL - FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Design and development of custom websites for SMEs - 01/2015 - 07/2015

I developed websites for different clients and projects for the public administration:

- Back: Programming with PHP and MySQL
- Front: Programming with **¡Query** and CSS3 (SASS)
- Content layout through **Responsive Design** with Foundation
- CMS: Creation of websites in Wordpress and Joomla
- eCommerce: Creating stores with Prestashop
- Use of Search Engine Optimization techniques
- Contact, advice and development of customised projects according to the requirements of the client

EDUCATION

MASTER'S DEGREE IN WEB ENGINEERING

University of Oviedo - 2013 - 2015

Postgraduate Master (two years) of the European Higher Education Area (EHEA) where I obtained a knowledge specialised in:

- Front-end web development (HTML5, CSS3, SASS, **jQuery** and **AngularJS**)
- Programming methodologies in Java, **PHP**, and basic **NodeJS** concepts
- Development of web applications using design patterns and web services
- Advanced concepts of usability, accessibility and web positioning (SEO)
- Application development on Android mobile devices (Java 7)
- Administration and programming in CMS: Joomla and Wordpress (theme)
- Semantic Web Training (Schema and structured data)

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

University of Oviedo - 2008 - 2013

First cycle degree where I acquire competences in:

- Programming in C++ and Java
- Basic web concepts (HTML and CSS)
- Server Administration: Windows and **Linux**
- Mathematical study and analysis
- Modelling problems using UML
- Relational database design
- Design patterns, refactoring and good practices

REFERENCES

Marcos Icardo

Co-founder de Fintonic marcos.icardo@gmail.com

Angel Luengo

Co-founder de 24symbols angel@metastartup.com

Alfredo Alvarez

CTO de Envista alfredo.alvarez@envista.es